Finding Aid for Alpheus Felch papers 1817-1896
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Alpheus Felch Papers
1817-1896
Felch, Alpheus, 1804-1896.
851648 Aa 2; AC; Ac
Lawyer, Member of Michigan Supreme Court, 1842-1846, Democratic Governor of Michigan, 1846-1847, and holder of numerous other public offices; papers include correspondence and other papers documenting his career in public service.
6 linear feet
6 oversize volumes
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was received from Felch family members in 1949 and 1981. Donor numbers 923, 2671
The collection is open for research.
Alpheus Felch was born in Limmerick, York County, Maine, on September 23, 1804. He died in Ann Arbor, Michigan, on June 13, 1896. Felch's career as a lawyer and politician crisscrossed the United States, although the majority of his life was devoted to service in his adopted state of Michigan.
Orphaned at the age of three, Alpheus Felch was raised by his paternal grandfather, and later a family friend, Edmund Hayes. In 1821 Felch entered Phillips Exeter Academy, at Exeter, New Hampshire. Financial problems led Felch to become a school teacher and to finish his initial schooling at the academy in Fryeburg, Maine. In 1823 Alpheus Felch was admitted to the freshman class at Bowdoin College, where he continued to supplement his income with teaching assignments. He graduated from Bowdoin in 1827.
In pursuit of a legal career, Felch entered the offices of Bradley and Barrow in Fryeburg and later continued his training in Bangor, Maine. Alpheus Felch was admitted to the bar in 1830, and almost immediately was commissioned to recover a law library in Houlton, Maine. He remained there in the practice of law until 1833, when he undertook a journey to the South for reasons of health. A combination of factors, including the contraction of Cholera, led Felch to Monroe, Michigan. He settled in Monroe until 1843, when Ann Arbor became his permanent residence.
Alpheus Felch's first political position was that of Monroe County representative in the State legislature, 1835-1837. He then served as State Bank Commissioner in 1838 and 1839, and is credited with exposing much of the corruption associated with "wild cat" banking. In 1842 Felch was made Auditor General of the state, but was appointed to the State Supreme Court only a few weeks later, upon the resignation of Judge William A. Fletcher. Felch served in this position until 1845, when he was elected governor.
Alpheus Felch served as governor of Michigan from January 5, 1846, to March 3, 1847, when he resigned this office upon his election to the United States Senate. Felch served in the Senate from March 4, 1847, to March 3, 1853. He was an active member on the Committee on Public Lands, and during his final four years in office was its chairman.
In 1853 Felch was appointed president of the commission to settle land claims in California. This commission acted upon Spanish, Mexican, and American claims to lands in California from 1853 to 1856. In June of 1856, with the commission's work complete, Felch returned to Ann Arbor and the practice of law. In the spring of 1879 he was appointed Tappan law professor at the University of Michigan, a position from which Felch resigned in 1883. Alpheus Felch remained an active figure in his later years, serving as president of the Michigan State Historical Society from 1888 to 1894.
Alpheus Felch married Lucretia Williams Lawrence of Monroe, Michigan, on September 14, 1837. They had eight children, five sons and three daughters. Mrs. Felch died on July 30, 1882.
The Alpheus Felch collection came to the library in two separate accessions, the first in 1949, and the second in 1981. Because the core of each accession was correspondence and because the collection had been heavily researched, the decision was made in 1981 not to interfile the letters but rather to create two separate series for Felch's correspondence. In addition to correspondence, the other series in the collection consist of personal and family materials; records detailing Felch's work with the U.S. Commission to Settle Private Land Claims in California, 1853-1856; legal, financial, and miscellaneous files; and photographs.
The Alpheus Felch papers details the active life of this nineteenth century Michigan public servant. Not only are public issues discussed in the correspondence files but the researcher will also gain an understanding of some of the personal problems associated with public service. The collection also includes several files of other family members.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Banks and banking--United States.; Barry, John Stewart, 1802-1870.; Bingham, Kinsley S. (Kinsley Scott), 1808-1861.; California.; Canada--History--Rebellion, 1837-1838.; Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866.; Democratic Party (Mich.); Elections--Michigan--1856.; Felch, Alpheus, 1804-1896.; Flint (Mich.); Indians of North America.; Land use--California.; Lapeer (Mich.); Maine.; Martineau, Harriet, 1802-1876.; Michigan State Capitol (Lansing, Mich.); Michigan Central Railroad Company.; Michigan Manual Labor School (Ann Arbor); Upper Peninsula (Mich.); Michigan--Politics and government--1815-1844.; Michigan--Politics and government--1845-1860.; Michigan--Politics and government--1861-1865.; Michigan--Politics and government--1866-1876.; Michigan--Politics and government--1877-1898.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1841-1850.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1851-1860.; Michigan Soldiers Relief Association.; Michigan. Supreme Court.; Mines and mineral resources--United States.; Minnesota.; Monroe (Mich.); Presidents--United States--Election--1848.; Presidents--United States--Election--1852.; Sault Sainte Marie (Mich.); Taylor, Charles Coffin, 1805-1855.; United States. Congress. House.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States--Politics and government--19th century.; University of Michigan. Board of Regents.; University of Michigan--Faculty.Faculty.; University of Michigan--History.History.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Law.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Medicine and Surgery.; Mexican War, 1846-1848.; Governors--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Cole family.; Death.; Delta Kappa Epsilon. Omicron Chapter (University of Michigan); Dwellings--Michigan--Monroe.; Felch, Alpheus, 1804-1896.; Felch family.; Indians of North America.; Kawbawgam, Charles, d. 1902.; Lawrence family.; Monroe (Mich.)--Dwellings.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; University of Michigan--Students.Students.
Contributors:
Adam, John J., 1807-1888.; Adams, Charles Kendall, 1835-1902.; Agnew, John Holmes, 1804-1865.; Alger, R. A. (Russell Alexander), 1836-1907.; Allen, Edward Payson, 1839-1909.; Allen, John, 1796-1851.; Anderson, William, b. 1843.; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Angell, Sarah Caswell, 1831-1903.; Bancroft, William L., b. 1825.; Bates, George C., 1813-1886.; Bell, Digby V., 1784-1871.; Bishop, Levi, 1815-1881.; Bradbury, James Ware, 1802-1901.; Brady, Mathew B., 1823 (ca.)-1896.; Bridge, Samuel J.; Brown, Joseph W., 1793-1880.; Brown, William S., 1821-1891.; Buel, Alexander Woodruff, 1813-1868.; Burt, Hiram Austin, b. 1839.; Burt, John.; Burt, William Austin, 1792-1858.; Butler, Benjamin F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1818-1893.; Butler, Charles, 1802-1897.; Campbell, James V. (James Valentine), 1823-1890.; Carpenter, Guy, 1808-1849.; Chase, Salmon P. (Salmon Portland), 1808-1873.; Chipman, Henry C., 1784-1867.; Christiancy, Isaac Peckham, 1812-1890.; Comstock, Addison J., 1802-1867.; Comstock, O. C. (Oliver Cromwell), 1780-1860.; Cook, D. B.; Cooley, Thomas McIntyre, 1824-1898.; Crane, Flavius J. B., 1812-1886.; Crary, Isaac Edwin, 1804-1854.; Cushing, Caleb, 1800-1879.; Danforth, George, d. 1856.; Denton, Samuel, 1803-1860.; Dodge, Henry M.; Douglass, Samuel Townsend, 1814-1898.; Dunham, Nelson, 1803-1866.; Eldridge, Robert P., d. 1884.; Ewing, Thomas, 1789-1871.; Felch, Caroline.; Felch, Lucretia, d. 1882.; Felch, Theodore A., b. 1847.; Gillet, Ransom H. (Ransom Hooker), 1800-1876.; Goodrich, Enos, 1813-1897.; Goodrich, Reuben, 1819-1899.; Grant, Claudius Buchanan, 1835-1921.; Griswold, George R., d. 1857.; Gunn, Moses, 1822-1887.; Hale, William, 1809-1874.; Hall, Frederick, 1816-1883.; Hill, George D., 1820-1881.; Howard, Jacob Merritt, 1805-1871.; Hunt, James B., 1799-1857.; Ingersoll, John N., 1817-1881.; Jackson, Calvin C., 1814-1883.; Jones, George Wallace, 1804-1896.; Joslin, C., 1813-1889.; Kearsley, Jonathan, 1786-1859.; Kellogg, John R., 1793-1868.; Knox, John Jay, 1828-1892.; Lamb, Jonathan.; Landon, Rufus W., 1815-1886.; Lathrop, H. B., 1808-1890.; Lawrence, Edwin A.; Lawrence, William Wolcott.; Lothrop, Edwin H., 1806-1874.; Lothrop, George Van Ness, 1817-1897.; Luce, Cyrus Gray, 1824-1905.; Lyon, Lucius, 1800-1851.; McClelland, Robert, 1807-1880.; McGaffey, Neal.; Mann, C. M.; Marsh, Owen.; Mason, Emily.; Mason, Stevens Thomson, 1811-1843.; Morey, Peter, 1798-1881.; Morse, Richard E., 1809-1865.; Nichols, Joseph.; Noble, Charles, 1797-1874.; Noble, David A., 1806-1896.; Norris, Lyman, 1823-1894.; Noyes, Horace A., 1810-1877.; Palmer, Charles Henry, 1814-1887.; Parsons, Philo.; Piper, Horace.; Platt, Zephaniah, 1797-1872.; Polk, James K. (James Knox), 1795-1849.; Pond, Elihu Bartlit, 1826-1898.; Prescott, R. F.; Price, Lyman B., b. 1811.; Prichette, Kintzing.; Ransom, Epaphroditus, 1797-1859.; Redfield, Alexander Heman, 1805-1869.; Rich, John Treadway, 1841-1926.; Richmond, William A., 1808-1870.; Schwarz, J. E., 1799-1858.; Shearer, Jonathan, 1796-1881.; Shook, Jacob, 1779-1862.; Sibley, John Langdon, 1804-1885.; Silver, Abiel, 1797-1881.; Smith, Henry, d. 1847.; Spencer, Sheldon.; Stone, Hiram.; Swineford, A. P. (Alfred P.), 1834-1909.; Taylor, Charles H., b. 1813.; Taylor, Helen M.; Ten Eyck, Anthony.; Terry, Henry D., 1814-1869.; Thurber, Jefferson G., 1807-1857.; Trowbridge, C. A.; Truesdale family.; United States. Commission for Ascertaining and Settling Private Land Claims in California.; United States. General Land Office.; United States. Pension Bureau.; Upson, Charles, 1821-1885.; Walker, Henry N. (Henry Nelson), 1811-1886.; Webber, William Lewis, 1825-1901.; Weston, J. W.; Whipple, Charles Whiley, 1805-1855.; White, Peter, 1830-1908.; Whitney, Asa, 1797-1872.; Williams, Asa, 1802-1869.; Williams, Joseph R., 1808-1861.; Wilson, John, 1822-1907.; Wilson, Robert S., d. 1883.; Wing, Austin Eli, 1792-1849.; Woodbridge, William, 1780-1861.; Woodruff, John G.; Wright, Dorothea Mason.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.; Prints.
- Correspondence and other papers (1949 accession), 1822-1896
  Correspondence and other Papers (1949 accession) is a chronologically arranged series and dates from 1822 to 1896. The letters concern family affairs, business, state and national politics, particularly the presidential candidacy of Lewis Cass and the elections of 1848 and 1852, and the Felch estate.
  - 1822-1825 (Box 1)
  - 1830-1835 (Box 1)
  - 1836-1840 (Box 1)
  - 1841-1842 (Box 1)
  - 1843 (Box 1)
  - 1844 (Box 1)
  - 1845 (Box 1)
  - 1846 (Box 1)
  - January 1847-September 1847 (Box 1)
  - October 1847-December 1847 (Box 1)
  - January 1848 (Box 1)
  - February 1848 (Box 1)
  - March 1848 (Box 1)
  - April 1848 (Box 1)
  - May 1848 (Box 1)
  - June 1848 (Box 1)
  - July 1848-September 1848 (Box 1)
  - October 1848-December 1848 (Box 1)
  - January 1849-June 1849 (Box 1)
  - July 1849-December 1849 (Box 1)
  - January 1850-June 1850 (Box 1)
  - July 1850-December 1850 (Box 1)
  - 1851 (Box 1)
  - 1852 (Box 1)
  - 1853 (Box 1)
  - 1854 (Box 1)
  - 1855 (Box 1)
  - 1856-1860 (Box 1)
  - 1861-1870 (Box 1)
  - 1871-1880 (Box 1)
  - 1881-1890 (Box 1)
  - 1891-1895 (Box 1)
  - 1896 (Box 1)
  - Undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence (1981 accession), 1817-1896
  Correspondence and other Papers (1981 accession) consists of two subseries: Chronological and Alphabetical. This Chronological subseries dates from 1817 to 1896. The Alphabetical subseries includes letters received from such notable figures as: James W. Bradbury, Samuel J. Bridge, Lewis Cass, C. C. Jackson, Robert C. McClelland, Owen March, Kintzing Prichette, Anthony Ten Eyck, and William Woodbridge. Personal correspondence with Mrs. Lucretia Felch and Edwin A. Lawrence (brother-in-law) provide information on a wide variety of political and social subjects.
  - Chronological
    - (John Felch), 1817 (Box 1)
    - 1824-1827 (Box 1)
    - 1828-1829 (Box 1)
    - 1830 (Box 1)
    - 1831 (Box 1)
    - 1832-1834 (Box 1)
    - 1835 (Box 1)
    - January 1836-June 1836 (Box 1)
    - July 1836-December 1836 (Box 1)
    - 1837 (Box 1)
    - January 1838-June 1838 (Box 2)
    - July 1838-December 1838 (Box 2)
    - January 1839-June 1839 (Box 2)
    - July 1839-December 1839 (Box 2)
    - 1840 (Box 2)
    - 1841-1843 (Box 2)
    - 1845 (Box 2)
    - January 1846-June 1846 (Box 2)
    - July 1846-December 1846 (Box 2)
    - January 1847-June 1847 (Box 2)
    - July 1847-December 1847 (Box 2)
    - January 1848-March 1848 (Box 2)
    - April 1848 (Box 2)
    - May 1848 (Box 2)
    - June 1848 (Box 2)
    - July 1848-December 1848 (Box 2)
    - January 1849-June 1849 (Box 2)
    - July 1849-December 1849 (Box 2)
    - January 1850-March 1850 (Box 2)
    - April 1850-June 1850 (Box 2)
    - July 1850-December 1850 (Box 2)
    - 1851 (Box 2)
    - January 1852-June 1852 (Box 2)
    - July 1852-December 1852 (Box 2)
    - January 1853-June 1853 (Box 2)
    - July 1853-December 1853 (Box 2)
    - 1854 (Box 2)
    - 1855-1856 (Box 2)
    - 1856 (Box 2)
      (telegrams regarding convention and election)
    - 1857-1858 (Box 2)
    - 1859-1880 (Box 2)
    - 1881-1886 (Box 2)
    - 1887-1889 (Box 2)
    - 1890-1892 (Box 2)
    - 1893-1896 (Box 3)
    - Undated and unidentified (including postcards) (Box 3)
  - Alphabetical subseries
    - A, 1 folders (Box 3)
      - Adams, Charles K., June 1, 1886; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Agnew, Rev. J. H., 1852; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Alger, R. A., 1886-1891; 5 items (Box 3)
      - Allen, Edward P., 1889; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Allen, John, January 16, 1850; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Ambler, William E., 1888; 3 items (Box 3)
      - Anderson, William E., 1846-1852; 3 items (Box 3)
      - Angell, James B., 1877-1885; 7 items (Box 3)
      - Angell, Sarah C., May 23, 1883; 1 items (Box 3)
    - Ba-Bn, 1 folders
      - Baldwin, Roger S., January 24, 1850; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Bancroft, E. C., July 24, 1840; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Bancroft, William L., 1850; 1885; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Barry, John S., 1840; 1850; 3 items (Box 3)
      - Bayles, N., 1851-1852; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Beal, Junius E., October 13, 1885; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Begole, Josiah W., 1889; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Bell, Digby V., 1842; 1846; 9 items (Box 3)
      - Bingham, Kinsley S., April 9, 1849; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Bishop, Levi, January 1, 1863; 1 items (Box 3)
    - Bo-Bz, 1 folders
      - Board of World's Fair Managers for Michigan, 1892-1893; 10 items (Box 3)
      - Bowdoin College, 1878-1893; 6 items (Box 3)
      - Brady, Mathew B., February 13, 1849; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Brown, B. F., 1859; 6 items (Box 3)
      - Brown, Joseph W., 1835; 1846; 1850; 8 items (Box 3)
      - Brown, William S., 1842-1853; 7 items (Box 3)
      - Burt, Hiram T., 1889; 4 items (Box 3)
      - Burt, John, December 6, 1854; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Burt, William A., 1850-1851; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Butler, Charles, 1846; 2 items (Box 3)
    - Bradbury, James W., 1851-1895 (Box 3)
    - Bridge, Samuel J., 1854-1892 (Box 3)
    - C, 1 folders
      - Campbell, J. T., 1889; 3 items (Box 3)
      - Campbell, J. V., 1882; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Carpenter, Guy, 1846; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Chase, Salmon P., 1852; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Chipman, Henry C., 1850-1851; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Christiancy, I. P. (and others), 1848-1849; 3 items (Box 3)
        (includes slavery petition)
      - Cole, Lawrence T., 1892; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Comstock, Addison J., 1838-1839; 7 items (Box 3)
      - Comstock, Oliver C., 1850; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Cook, D. B., 1889; 4 items (Box 3)
      - Cooley, Thomas McIntyre, 1846-1887; 6 items (Box 3)
      - Crane, Flavius J. B., July 17, 1848; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Crary, Isaac E., June 28, 1836; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Cushing, Caleb, August 21, 1854; 1 items (Box 3)
    - Cass, Lewis, 1838-1859 (Box 3)
    - D-E, 1 folders
      - Democratic Central Association, 1856; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Denton, Samuel, December 11, 1847; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Dickinson, Donald M., 1890; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Dunbar, Charles F., November 7, 1894; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Dunham, Nelson, 1846-1855; 6 items (Box 3)
      - Ewing, Thomas, June 10, 1850; 1 items (Box 3)
    - Felch (miscellaneous)
      - Felch, Alvan, 1847-1848; 3 items (Box 3)
      - Felch, Amos, 1879-1889; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Felch, Charles P., 1848-1889; 11 items (Box 3)
      - Felch, F. L., 1877-1893; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Felch, James H., 1858; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Felch, T. A., 1935-1937; 3 items (Box 3)
    - Felch, Caroline, 1852-1858; 19 items (Box 3)
      (typescripts)
    - Felch, Lucretia, 1836-1856; 4 folders (Box 3)
    - G, 1 folders
      - Gillet, Ransom H., April 14, 1858; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Goodrich, Enos, 1850; 1888; 1894; 3 items (Box 3)
      - Goodrich, Reuben, March 27, 1893; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Grant, C. B., 1881-1892; 6 items (Box 3)
      - Griswold, George R., 1845; 1848; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Gunn, Moses, July 22, 1852; 1 items (Box 3)
    - H-I, 1 folders
      - Hale, William, 1842-1852; 10 items (Box 3)
      - Hall, Frederick, December 2, 1850; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Hill, George D., 1846-1881; 8 items (Box 3)
      - Hopkinson, Julia, 1825-1839; 8 items (Box 3)
      - Howard, J. M., 1837; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Hunt, James B., 1847; 1851; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Ingersoll, John N., February 22, 1848; 1 items (Box 3)
    - J, 1 folders
      - Jones, George W., 1849; 1889-1894; 11 items (Box 3)
      - Joslyn, C. (Joslin), 1845; 2 items (Box 3)
    - Jackson, C. C., 1836-1882 (Box 3)
    - K, 1 folders
      - Kearsley, J., 1845-1846; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Kellogg, John, June 4, 1850; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Knox, John J., February 8, 1887; 1 items (Box 3)
    - La-Ln, 1 folders
      - Lamb, Jonathan, 1846-1848; 7 items (Box 3)
      - Landon, Rufus W., October 1, 1840; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Lathrop, H. B., July 30, 1845; 1 items (Box 3)
      - Lawrence, William Wolcott, 1845-1849; 4 items (Box 3)
    - Lo-Lz, 1 folders
      - Lothrop, Edwin H., 1840; 1847; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Lothrop, George Van Ness, 1850-1879; 7 items (Box 3)
      - Lougee Family, 1887-1888; 12 items (Box 3)
      - Luce, Cyrus G., 1887; 1889; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Lyon, Lucius, 1834-1849; 4 items (Box 3)
      - Lyons, Edwin C., 1893; 5 items (Box 3)
    - Lawrence, Edwin A., 1846-1882; 2 folders; 91 items (Box 3)
    - M, 1 folders (Box 4)
      - McGaffey, Neal, 1838; 1848; 1851-1852; 4 items (Box 4)
      - McDonald, Moses, 1833-1834; 2 items (Box 4)
      - Magazine of Western History, 1886; 2 items (Box 4)
      - Mann, C. M. (Michigan Central Railroad), 1858; 6 items (Box 4)
      - Mason, Emily, 1890-1891; 9 items (Box 4)
      - Mason, Stevens T., 1835; 1838; 2 items (Box 4)
      - Michigan Legislative Association, 1886; 2 items (Box 4)
      - Moore, J. B., December 9, 1893; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Morey, Peter, October 14, 1838; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Morse, Richard E., 1840; 1853; 2 items (Box 4)
    - McClelland, Robert C., 1844-1855; 2 folders; 60 items (Box 4)
    - Marsh, Owen, 1845-1854; 30 items (Box 4)
    - N, 1 folders
      - Nichols, Joseph, 1834-1838; 14 items (Box 4)
      - Noble, Charles, September 10, 1860; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Noble, David A., March 19, 1892; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Norris, Lyman D., March 18, 1882; 1 items (Box 4)
    - P, 1 folders
      - Page, Evelyn, November 19, 1890; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Page, Sarah Felch, 1820-1836; 12 items (Box 4)
      - Palmer, Charles H., December 23, 1850; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Parsons, Philo, 1882; 2 items (Box 4)
      - Platt, Zephaniah, August 2, 1852; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Plumbe, John, April 1848; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Polk, James K. (letters to), January 1847; 5 items (Box 4)
      - Pond, Elihu B., November 14, 1893; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Pratt, James T., February 20, 1854; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Prescott, R. F., March 11, 1879; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Price, Lyman B., August 8, 1848; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Prichette, Kintzing, 1838-1840; 8 items (Box 4)
    - Pyser, Horace, 1885-1891 (Box 4)
    - Q-R, 1 folders
      - Quimby, William E., 1891; 4 items (Box 4)
      - Ransom, Epaphroditus, June 2, 1849; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Rich, John T., 1893; 2 items (Box 4)
      - Richmond, William A., 1845-1852; 4 items (Box 4)
      - Russell, Alfred, 1889; 2 items (Box 4)
    - S, 1 folders
      - Schwarz, J. E., 1846-1850; 3 items (Box 4)
      - Semi-Centennial Commission, 1886; 2 items (Box 4)
      - Shearer, Jonathan, 1845-1846; 1853; 3 items (Box 4)
      - Shoemaker, M., June 16, 1893; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Shook, Jacob, 1845; 1849; 2 items (Box 4)
      - Sibley, John L., December 2, 1847; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Silver, Abiel, 1846; 4 items (Box 4)
      - Smith, Henry, July 17, 1846; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Spencer, Sheldon, 1835-1838; 3 items (Box 4)
      - Stacy, Consider A., August 25, 1845; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Steere, Joseph H., November 30, 1893; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Stone, Hiram, 1846; 4 items (Box 4)
      - Stuart, Charles E., 1848; 1885; 2 items (Box 4)
      - Swineford, Albert P., November 17, 1883; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Syracuse Insurance Company, 1846; 4 items (Box 4)
    - T, 1 folders
      - Taylor, Charles H., June 22, 1850; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Taylor, Helen M., 1883-1888; 6 items (Box 4)
      - Ten Eyck, Anthony, 1847-1852; 8 items (Box 4)
      - Terry, Henry D., February 24, 1840; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Thurber, Jefferson G., August 9, 1856; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Trowbridge, C. A., 1850-1852; 3 items (Box 4)
      - Truesdale Family (Aaron D. and George E.), 1854; 3 items (Box 4)
    - U, 1 folders
      - University of Michigan Board of Regents, 1883; 1888; 2 items (Box 4)
      - Upson, Charles, February 2, 1881; 1 items (Box 4)
    - U.S. Office of the Commission to Settle Private Land Claims in California, 1852-1856; undated; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - U.S. General Land Office, 1848-1854 (Box 4)
    - U.S. Pension Office, 1848-1852 (Box 4)
    - Wa-Wh, 1 folders
      - Walker, Henry N., 1845-1852; 11 items (Box 4)
      - Webber, William, 1888-1889; 3 items (Box 4)
      - Weston, J. W., January 8, 1891; 1 items (Box 4)
      - White, Peter, April 4, 1858; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Whitney, Asa, 1848-1853; 8 items (Box 4)
    - Wi-Wz, 1 folders
      - Williams, Asa, December 11, 1848; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Williams, Joseph, September 22, 1846; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Wilson, John, July 22, 1852; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Wing, A. E., 1835; 2 items (Box 4)
      - Woodbridge, William, 1852; 3 items (Box 4)
      - Woodruff, John G., August 5, 1852; 1 items (Box 4)
      - Wright, Dorothia Mason, 1891; 7 items (Box 4)
- Personal Files
  The Personal Files includes biographical information, family and genealogical materials, and student papers.
  - Alpheus Felch (Box 4)
    - Biographical Sketches (clippings) (Box 4)
    - Family and personal information (Box 4)
    - Land grants, appointments, etc., 6 items in oversize folder (Box 4)
    - Obituaries (typescripts) (Box 4)
    - "Alpheus Felch: An Appreciation", by Herbert Randall (Michigan History Magazine, April 1926) (Box 4)
    - Sketch by T. A. Felch, 1933 (Box 4)
  - Daniel Felch
    - Letters, circa 1794-1804 (Box 4)
    - Papers relating to the estate of D. Felch, 1815-1820 (Box 4)